[Music]
in 2024 release wave two you can now
conditionally apply uh configuration
templates to the data that you
synchronize between data ver and
business Central my name is Ivan ktic
and I'm a product manager in business
Central engineering team and I want you
to join me for the next couple of
minutes to see this new capability in
action so business is often enriched
data that's synchronized between
business Central and dataor by using
templates to make uh data ready to use
either in business Central or in data
verse having this configurable
rule-based and automated way uh to
select the templates to apply when you
synchronize data and when you create new
records means that you don't have to
extend your integration Solutions which
such rules and the integration between
business Central and data verse uh and
the 365 uh apps is faster and more uh
cost effective so let's go ahead and see
U what Auto apply templates in
integration with data verse looks like
in action so the place where we do apply
this configuration templates to be
applied when the data is synchronized is
in the integration table mappings so
let's go and open the integration table
mappings and see how it looks like we'll
work with a customer I've set up a
couple of templates so that once the new
customers are created from uh data ver
they they got apply different templates
based on the country code that the
customer has the the first thing that
you may notice uh right now is when you
have only one template the name of the
template to be applied is displayed in
the integration table mappings but when
you have more more templates and they
have some conditions or some rules on
how these templates are applied you will
see the number of templates so let's
have a look at this as you can see I
have a sort of a default uh template
that gets applied when a country code is
set to uh us or it's uh blank I have the
EU template that gets applied uh when
any of these uh EU countries are uh are
added and this is the third template
that I'll apply for all other countries
I'll just reuse a filter that I have in
here to set this up
so the foreign configuration template
code is going to be applied when a
country region
code is different from all of these and
it's different from us given this is a
US company so anything that's not EU or
that's not us should actually get uh
this
template now another thing that you can
actually do in here is you can actually
set the priority of evaluation so once
the new record gets created we will go
uh one by one and see which of these uh
which of these conditions are met and
the priority field just uh shows the
order of evaluation of this right so
what I'll do I'll set this one to be
three and this one to be two which means
that the default is going to be uh
evaluated first then we'll look at the
foreign and then if the the record does
not satisfy the conditions that we set
in the filter in here then it's going to
evaluate the eu1 right so so to see how
this actually uh Works in action I have
a
account that I've uh this contoso BCL
and as you can see it has the Australian
country region code so when I go ahead
and create in business
Central uh the the thing that I want to
see is that that foreign template gets
applied and that foreign template I
forgot to show you actually contains a
customer posting group for it right as
opposed to the other ones that get
posted to other uh receivables account
so let's create this in business Central
and see what the effect of this is see
if it's
finished okay it has finished and let's
see the result of of that so this was a
completely uh a completely new customer
that we have taken from data verse and
put it in uh business Central let's have
a look at this customer
so I have ktoo
ble which is a new customer that uh we
synchronized and if we look at the
customer posting group you can see it is
foreign right just to uh show you once
more you can actually see that
that
um configuration template actually
had the customer posting group for in
set and it got applied after meeting
those conditions uh that we've
specified okay so what we saw in the
demo is that there are new configuration
template setup pages that you can access
through a drill down from the
integration uh table mapping you can set
the you can set a uh sort of conditions
by defining a filter that needs to be
satisfied in order for template to be uh
applied and you can also Define the
evaluation priorities or the order in
which uh different uh template filters
are going to be evaluated before
the uh before a specific template is
applied what I shown you in um in in the
short demo was the application of the
table configuration template which means
this is a template that gets applied
once the data ver record gets created in
business Central but there's also
integration table configuration
templates which apply for when um
business Central um record is actually
created in data ver so it works in uh in
both uh in both
directions and that was it so I hope you
really enjoyed the the video and uh I
also hope that you go ahead and uh try
out this uh new feature uh for
additional uh material check out the
description below uh the video and for
additional links also in the in the
caption uh below the video thank you